operaunite.com 2016-06-17

# Privacy Statement | Opera

_Updated May 6, 2016_

### Summary

We at Opera Software AS ("Opera") take your privacy seriously. This privacy statement explains what data we collect, how we store and transfer it and how we use it. The exact set of the data we collect, its purpose and your opt-out choices depend on the product or service you use. Please refer to the relevant product or service sections of this privacy statement to learn more specific details.

Some of the data we collect, either individually or aggregated, may be considered personal. We treat this data in a special way, as required by law.

We'll always honor your decisions for how your data is used. We have safeguards in place to protect your data from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

When we post changes to this privacy statement, we will include the date when the statement was last updated. If we significantly change this statement or how we use your personal information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice prior to implementing the change or by sending you a notification directly. We encourage you to respect review this statement periodically.

### Why we collect data?

We only process your data for purposes that are objectively justified by our products and services. We process this data with respect to your fundamental right to privacy, including the need to protect personal integrity and private life and to ensure that your personal data is of adequate quality. Unless otherwise stated, we determine the purposes for and manners in which your data is collected (in legalese, we act as a "data controller" regarding personal data).

We collect data to:

  * Improve, debug, and maintain Opera products and services
  * Study and personalize user experiences
  * Fulfill legal requirements
  * Conduct business analysis and research, and marketing campaigns
  * Ensure better security and fraud protection

We may also use your data to send personalized information regarding updates, upgrades, enhancements, surveys, recommendations and/or advertisements, if we believe these are relevant for you.

### What data we collect?

The information we collect may include: personal data, for example your name, email, IP-address, location; and non-personal technical data, for example who manufactured your device, your screen's resolution, your mobile operator's region and code. A complete list of the data we collect and purpose of collection may vary between our products and services. You can find detailed descriptions in the product/service-related sections below.

### How we collect data?

Generally, we collect data:

  * When you provide it explicitly to us; for example, when you submit a form on our websites
  * When you use our products and services, or visit our websites
  * When third parties share information with us

Some products may require your personal data to function properly. Wherever technically possible, we'll ask for your consent to collect your personal data and offer you the choice to opt-out. Please read product-specific information to learn how to opt-out.

When we collect your data, we associate it with a unique ID and a unique device ID that are generated when you install an Opera product or begin using one of our services. These identifiers are anonymized and cannot be linked to you as an individual person. We also take measures to remove any possible connections between these IDs and other types of personal data.

To collect information automatically, we may use [cookies](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie), [web beacons](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_beacon), our own data-collection tools or various third-party services.

Some third-party sites may monitor data traffic from our products and services, such as numbers of hits and the search terms used. We do not make available any personally identifiable information to these services.

This privacy statement does not cover third-party apps you access and use through our products and services, nor does it cover links to other websites. We do not control the privacy and security practices and policies of these third parties and their sites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of the third-party apps and websites you use.

### How we protect your data?

We treat your personal data as required by law. We are a Norwegian company and we follow Norwegian data-security laws as well as other national legislation, as needed. We require that our suppliers successfully pass security assessments and prove their compliance with applicable laws and industry standards.

Only a limited number of Opera employees have access to the data we collect. We review and update our working procedures regularly to improve your privacy and ensure that our internal policies are followed. We immediately correct any non-conformance regarding these policies.

Our commitment to your privacy does not extend to third-party products and services you may access from Opera products and services. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of the third-party products and services you use.

### How we share your data?

We may share your data:

  * To government bodies and law enforcement agencies to comply with the law, for example in judicial proceedings, by court order or other legal process
  * To third parties (including professional advisors) to enforce or defend our legal rights, including our terms and conditions
  * To a third-party purchaser or seller (including professional advisors) in connection with a corporate event such as a merger, business acquisition or insolvency situation
  * As described elsewhere in this statement

Some of our products and services include third-party technology or code that may use the collected data. We may share anonymized and/or aggregated sets of data with our partners and other trusted third parties.

Because we are an international company with data-centers around the world, your data may be transferred to countries which do not have the same level of data protection laws as those in the country where you are located. We will ensure that your data is protected to a strict standard.

### What else should I know?

We aim to be transparent as to what data we collect and how we use it. Your rights are not limited to consent and opt-out choices only. If you've provided personal information to us, you may change or modify this information at any time.

We retain personal data only as long as necessary for processing it in accordance with the purposes described in this statement, or as otherwise necessary to comply with applicable laws. When your data is no longer necessary or relevant for our purposes, or required by applicable laws, we take steps to have it deleted, aggregated or made anonymous.

You can find out if we hold any personal data about you by contacting us. You may be asked to prove your identification so that we can verify who is making the request. If we hold information about you, you can ask us to correct any mistakes and delete any excessive information.

### Contact information

If you have any questions about this statement or any privacy issues regarding Opera and our products or services, we can be reached by email [privacy@opera.com](mailto:privacy@opera.com) or by post at:

Opera Software AS  
P.O. Box 4214 Nydalen  
NO-0401 OSLO  
Norway

For privacy policies and questions specifically related to the Opera products and services, please see the appropriate section below:

  * Opera for computers
  * Opera for Android
  * Opera Coast
  * Opera Mini
  * Opera Mini for Android
  * Opera Mini for iOS
  * Opera Max
  * Opera websites
  * Opera services
